Finding aid for the Exhibit Collection of Near Eastern Manuscripts, 1492-1848 LSC.1656
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Book covers and artifacts
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 38; 1 lacquered book cover: paper-mâché; 108 × 65 mm. (Box 4)
    Black lacquered book cover with floral ornamentation and leather spine; flowers in a gilt border on recto, abstract floral design on verso.
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 39; 1 lacquered book cover: paper-mâché; 127 × 78 mm. (Box 4)
    Lacquered book cover with floral ornamentation and leather spine. Outside cover shows floral motif on a black background bordered in black and gold; inside cover shows flowering plant on red background bordered in black and gold.
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 40; 1 lacquered book cover (one board only): paper-mâché; 217 × 141 mm. (Box 4)
    Black lacquered book cover (one board only) with decorative floral ornamentation. Recto shows a dense flower design over a burgundy background, with black, gold, and floral borders; verso shows flowering plant on black background bordered in black and gold.
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 41; 1 leather book cover: paper-mâché: 151 × 76 mm. (Box 4)
    Brown leather book cover with blue cloth inlays, gilt painting, and leather spine.
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 42; 1 lacquered book cover: paper-mâché; 176 × 100 mm. (Box 4)
    Lacquered book cover (two separate boards) with decorative floral ornamentation. Outside cover shows floral motif on a green background, with black and gold borders; inside cover shows a white flowering plant on a red background, bordered in gold.
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 43; 1 lacquered book cover: paper-mâché; 337 × 210 mm. (Box 4)
    Lacquered book covers. Recto has a flower and bird illustration set inside a yellow circle against a green background with thin gilded borders. Verso has two illustrations, one on the top half of the board, and another on the bottom. These show a number of women in what seems to be sequences from a story. The figures are drawn in black outline, wearing green and red dresses, and are set against a dark yellow and green background with a red border. Both boards are in poor condition. There is badly faded text in red ink over one of the story illustrations; the first word of the text appears to be "majlis," meaning assembly, and the second word is "Zulaykha". The scene is probably from Jami's romance of Yisuf and Zulaykha (see ms. 1656/3), where Zulaykha and other women were so awestruck by Yisuf's beauty that they peel the skin of their hands instead of the fruits they are holding. The covers may have been designed to contain a version of Jami's versified romance (completed 1483 CE). Below these two words is the date 1043 AH (1633-4 CE).
  - [Book cover], n.d.; Manuscript no. 44; 1 lacquered book cover: paper-mâché; 365 × 227 mm. (Box 4)
    Lacquered book cover with decorative floral ornamentation and leather spine. Outside covers show a scene with three youths; inside covers show a white medallion design on a black background.
  - [Wallet], n.d.; Manuscript no. 45; 1 wallet (accessory item): leather and velvet; 78 × 140 × 35 mm. (Box 4)
    Faded red velvet sewn over leather. Embroidered with floral and geometric ornamentation; green leather border. Gold clasp on flap.